Guide to the John Caughlan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- John Caughlan papers, 1936-1999; 1950-1989; 0704-002; 32.39 cubic feet 32 boxes, two oversize folders and two vertical files
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1936-1999
    - Case Files
      - Domingo, Silme and Gene Viernes
        - Terri J. Mast [Executrix of Domingo's Estate] vs. Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company and Keerkor Bedayan
          - Retainer Agreement, 1982 (Box-folder 10/22)
          - Pleadings, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 10/23-11/4)
          - Deposition Summaries, 1983 (Box-folder 11/5)
          - Notes, 1981-1983, undated (Box-folder 11/6)
      - Drifka, Douglas (Drifka et al. vs. Brainard, et al.; Mobilization of the First Squadron of the Eighteenth Armored Division, National Guard - "First of the Eighteenth"; Illegal Deployment; Violation of Guardsmens' Rights)
        Also includes some materials from the related case of Allen et al. vs. Brainard et al.
        - Incoming Letters, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 11/7)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 11/8)
        - Pleadings
          - District Court, 1968 (Box-folder 11/9-10)
          - Court of Appeals, 1968 (Box-folder 11/11-14)
          - United States Supreme Court, 1968 (Box-folder 11/15)
        - Personal Histories of Plaintiffs, undated (Box-folder 11/16)
        - Retainer Agreements and Lists of Plaintiffs, 1968 (Box-folder 11/17)
        - Notes and Research Materials, 1968-1969, undated (Box-folder 11/18-19)
        - Related Cases, 1968 (Box-folder 11/20-22)
        - Clippings, 1968 (Box-folder 11/23)
      - Edmondson, John Ernest (Coast Guard Screening), 1950-1975 (Box-folder 11/24)
      - Edwards, Alvin (Racial Discrimination, Arrest without Warrant, Illegal Search and Seizure), undated (Box-folder 11/25)
      - Eickholt, Willem (Seizure of Property; Violation of Cuba Embargo)
        - General Correspondence of Legal Team, 1993 (Box-folder 11/26-28)
        - Miscellaneous Correspondence Regarding Case, 1993 (Box-folder 12/1)
          Includes correspondence seeking support from local legislators.
        - Petition, 1993 (Box-folder 12/2)
        - Legal Memorandum from Roy J. Moceri, 1993 (Box-folder 12/3-4)
        - Notes and Research Materials, 1993, undated (Box-folder 12/5-7)
        - Clippings, 1992-1993, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
      - Fagin, Ted (Court Martial), 1961, undated (Box-folder 12/9)
      - Fisher, Avalo Allison (False Statement Regarding Membership in Communist Party), circa 1955 (Box-folder 12/10)
      - Free Ballot Party (Certification of Party; Recovery of Fees; Sutherland, Kissler and Huff), 1968-1970 (Box-folder 12/11-12)
      - Fujimoto, Charles Kazuyuki; Pleadings (Smith Act), undated (Box-folder 12/13-18)
      - Garcia, George (Conscientious Objector), 1969, undated (Box-folder 12/19)
      - Gilbert, Michael (Worker's Compensation), 1990 (Box-folder 12/20)
      - Gonzalez-Cordoba, Samuel (Deportation; El Salvador), 1984-1986, undated (Box-folder 12/21-22)
      - Guilmet, George and Van Lydegraf (Proposal of Initiative 33, a declaration against the war in Vietnam), 1966, undated (Box-folder 12/23)
      - Hagen, James (Medical Release from Army), 1970, undated (Box-folder 12/24)
      - Heay, James (Correction of Military Record regarding Other-than-Honorable Discharge)
        - Incoming Letters, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 12/25)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 12/26)
        - General Correspondence
          - Of Heay Family and Others, Seeking or Expressing Support for Case, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 12/27)
          - Between James Heay and the United States Army, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 12/28)
        - Army Records of James Heay, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 12/29)
        - Notes, 1968, undated (Box-folder 12/30)
        - Petitions, Statements and Affidavits, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 12/31)
      - Hebert, Joseph (Wrongful Death; Police Shooting; Black Panthers)
        - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 12/32)
        - Memoranda, 1975 (Box-folder 12/33)
        - Police Reports, 1975 (Box-folder 12/34-35)
        - Statements, 1975 (Box-folder 12/36-37)
        - Inquest, 1975 (Box-folder 12/38)
        - Ephemera and Publicity Materials, 1975, undated (Box-folder 12/39)
        - Clippings, 1975 (Box-folder 12/40-41)
        - Notes, 1975, undated (Box-folder 12/42)
      - Heikkila, William (Deportation; Communist Party Membership), 1952, 1957 (Box-folder 13/1)
      - Heitz, Marilyn (Alaska Native Eligibility Claim, Tlingit and Haida Tribes)
        - Incoming Letters, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 13/2)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 13/3)
        - General Correspondence of Heitz Family Members (Box-folder 13/4)
        - Pleadings, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13/5-6)
        - Transcript of Proceedings, 1977 (Box-folder 13/7)
        - Exhibits, 1970-1977, undated (Box-folder 13/8)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 13/9)
      - Hodderson, Guerry (Freeway Hall Case; Freedom Socialist Party), 1986-1987, 1995, undated (Box-folder 13/10-11)
        Not Caughlan's case, but he provided an affidavit in support of Hodderson and the Freedom Socialist Party.
      - Huff, Henry P. (Smith Act)
        - Incoming Letters, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 13/12)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 13/13)
        - Pleadings, 1952-1957, undated (Box-folder 13/14-20)
        - Notes, undatead (Box-folder 13/21)
        - Ephemera, 1953 (Box-folder 13/22)
        - Collateral Cases; Dashbach vs. United States, Pettus vs. United States (Contempt of Court), undated (Box-folder 13/23)
      - International Association of Machinists (Amici Curiae in Swenson vs. Seattle Central Labor Council et al.; Representation of Employees), undated (Box-folder 13/24-26)
      - International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, Local 25 (Tacoma Smelter), 1959, undated (Box-folder 13/27-28)
      - Jackson, Richard (vs. Todd Shipyard; Workers' Compensation), 1977-1978 (Box-folder 13/29-31)
      - Jackson, Walter (Curfew), 1947 (Box-folder 13/32)
      - Jay, Cecil Reginald: Pleadings (Immigration), 1953-1955 (Box-folder 13/33-34)
      - Johnston, Harold and Nora Ann
        - Adoption, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 13/35-36)
        - Adoption, 1968-1970 (Vf 2738a)
        - Wills, 1967-1969, undated (Vf 2738b)
        - Property Transfers, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 13/37-38)
      - Johnston, Lana (Membership in Muckleshoot Tribe), 1997 (Box-folder 14/1)
      - Kohler, Charles: Transcripts (Kohler, Wolf, Mangaoang, Jay et al.; Immigration), 1950 (Box-folder 14/2-18)
      - Kusnitz, Rose (Immigration), 1956 (Box-folder 14/19)
      - Lagunilla, Matias: Pleadings (Contempt of Court), undated (Box-folder 14/20)
      - Lenske, Reuben (Income Tax Evasion, Amicus), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 14/21)
      - Levine, Hollie (vs. Bastyr University; Wages Withheld), 1997 (Box-folder 14/22)
      - Lima-Flores, José (also referred to as José Flores-Lima); (Immigration, Central America)
        - Incoming Letters, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 14/23)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1984-1987, undated (Box-folder 14/24)
        - Pleadings
          - Court of Appeals, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 14/25-26)
          - Department of Justice, 1986 (Box-folder 14/27)
          - Board of Immigration Appeals, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 14/28)
        - Department of Justice Administrative Record, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 14/29-30)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 14/31-15/1)
      - Lovett, Richard (Conscientious Objector), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15/2)
      - Luckman, George (Immigration), 1953 (Box-folder 15/3)
      - Mangaoang, Ernesto (Immigration/Deportation)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 15/4)
        - Pleadings, 1950, 1953 (Box-folder 15/5-6)
        - Exhibit: Decision in Deportation Proceedings, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 15/7)
      - McCarty, Rose: Pleadings (Medical Insurance Dispute), undated (Box-folder 15/8-9)
      - Mendez-Sanabria, Alfonso (Immigration), 1982 (Box-folder 15/10)
      - Mercator Industries (Breach of Contract; vs. Willem Eickholt)
        - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box-folder 15/11)
        - Pleadings, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15/12-13)
      - Montgomery, Mark (Violation of Enlistment Contract), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 15/14)
      - Morgan, James (Social Security Benefits), undated (Box-folder 15/15)
      - National Union of Marine Cooks and Stewards: Pleadings (Libel), undated (Box-folder 15/16-21)
      - Newlon, Norman (Conscientious Objector)
        - Incoming Letters, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 15/22)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 15/23)
        - Pleadings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 15/24)
        - Notes and Background Material, 1962-1967, undated (Box-folder 15/25)
      - Niukkanen, William (Communist Party; Deportation)
        Not Caughlan's case, but he submitted an amicus curiae brief. Niukkanen was also known as William Mackie.
        - Pleadings, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 15/26)
      - Orloff, Stanley J. (Doctors Draft Act), 1952 (Box-folder 15/27-28)
      - Osaki, Rei vs. Columbia Basin Project, Grant County, Washington (Appropriation of Land)
        - Incoming Letters, 1952-1956 (Box-folder 15/29)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 15/30)
        - Pleadings, 1955-1956, undated (Box-folder 15/31)
        - Notes and Background Material, 1954-1956, undated (Box-folder 15/32)
          The first folder contains six black-and-white photographs, presumably of the property in question.
      - Padgett, Clarence Wayne (Desertion from United States Army), 1987 (Box-folder 15/33)
      - Paine, Alice (American Friends' Service Committee; Hiroshima Day Committee; Illegal Transfer of Funds), 1966-1967, undated (Box-folder 15/34)
      - Pennock, William J.: Pleadings (Un-American Activities), 1947, undated (Box-folder 16/1)
      - Poll, Tom (Conscientious Objector), 1971, undated (Box-folder 16/2)
      - Progressive Citizens of America: Pleadings (Un-American Activities), 1947 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - Rabang, Henry: Pleadings (Immigration), 1955-1956, undated (Box-folder 16/4)
      - Rance, Willie and Siegfried Hesse (Police Misconduct, False Arrest): Deposition of Willie Rance, 1954 (Box-folder 16/5)
      - Ranta, Carl (Coast Guard Security Screening)
        This is one of a number of Coast Guard screening cases handled by Caughlan. Because it was the first of the group on which the Coast Guard took action, many of the related cases did not have their own case files, and thus have been kept with the Ranta case. Other clients were Elmer Allen, Stokes Chiles, Stephen Connolly, John Edmonson, Nels Ekroth, Meyer Schneider, Robert Krahl, Ronald Simpson and Thomas Normann. Separate case files exist for Milton Corley and Ronald Simpson (in this accession) and Stokes Chiles (in accession 704-001).
        - General Correspondence, 1957 (Box-folder 16/6)
        - Pleadings, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16/7)
        - Transcript, 1958 (Box-folder 16/8)
        - Loyalty Oath Questionnaire, undated (Box-folder 16/9)
        - Notes, 1956-1958, undated (Box-folder 16/10)
        - Related Cases, 1951-1958 (Box-folder 16.11)
      - Robel, Eugene (Subversive Actvities, Defense Industry; Security)
        Eugene Robel was an employee at Todd Shipyards in Seattle.
        - Incoming Letters, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 16/12)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 16/13)
        - Pleadings
          - District Court, 1963-1966, undated (Box-folder 16/14-15)
          - Court of Appeals, 1971 (Box-folder 16/16)
          - United States Supreme Court, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 16/17-20)
        - Publicity, 1966, undated (Box-folder 16/21)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 16/22)
      - Ruich, Tony
        - Immigration Case
          - Incoming Letters, 1984, undated (Box-folder 16/23)
          - Outgoing Letters, 1984 (Box-folder 16/24)
          - Pleadings, 1982-1984, undated (Box-folder 16/25)
          - Transcripts, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 16/26)
          - Notes, undated (Box-folder 16/27)
        - Apex Equipment Company vs. Ruich (Payment Dispute), 1984, undated (Box-folder 16/28)
      - Rystad, Tora (Immigration; Deportation), 1958-1970 (Box-folder 16/29)
        Includes two passport-size black-and-white photographs of Tora Rystad.
      - Schneider, Herbert (Coast Guard Security Screening)
        - Incoming Letters, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 16/30)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 16/31)
        - Pleadings
          - District Court, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 16/32-36)
          - United States Supreme Court, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 16/37-38)
        - Notes, 1967, undated (Box-folder 16/39)
        - Research Materials, 1965, undated (Box-folder 16/40-17/1)
      - Ship Scalers, Dry Dock and Miscellaneous Boat Yard Workers' Union, Local 541
        - Suit Against Laborers' International Union of North America (Mishandling of Union Funds; False Statements; Union Elections)
          - General Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 17/2)
          - Pleadings, 1973-1976, undated (Box-folder 17/3-9)
          - Exhibits, 1968-1974, undated (Box-folder 17/10-16)
          - Notes, 1971-1974, undated (Box-folder 17/17-19)
        - Yvonne M. Quiroga vs. Ship Scalers (Dispute over Payment of Wages)
          - Pleadings, 1986 (Box-folder 17/20)
          - Transcript, 1983 (Box-folder 17/21-22)
          - Notes, undated (Box-folder 17/23)
        - Press Conference Materials, 1986 (Box-folder 17/24)
      - Simpson, Ronald (Coast Guard Screening), 1952-1958 (Box-folder 17/25-26)
      - Stallings, Bob (Court Martial; Conscientious Objector), 1969 (Box-folder 17/27)
      - Steinlauf, Michael (George Jackson Brigade), 1977 (Box-folder 17/28)
      - Talbot, Charles (Washington State Bar Association Matter)
        - Incoming Letters, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 17/29)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 17/30)
        - Pleadings, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 18/1)
        - Notes, 1967, 1974, undated (Box-folder 18/2)
      - Thompson, William (Conscientious Objector), 1970 (Box-folder 18/3)
      - Vinnedge, Robert (Conscientious Objector; Court Martial)
        - General Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 18/4)
        - Pleadings, 1970, undated (Box-folder 18/5)
        - Record of Trial, Verbatim, 1970 (Box-folder 18/6-7)
        - Notes, 1969, undated (Box-folder 18/8)
      - Waldman, Selma (Demonstration), 1969-1971 (Box-folder 18/9)
      - Ware, Frank (Selective Service), 1968-1972, undated (Box-folder 18/10-13)
      - Washington Environmental Council (vs. Port of Pasco; Nuclear Issues; Food Irradiation)
        - Incoming Letters to Legal Team, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 18/14-15)
        - Outgoing Letters of Legal Team, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 18/16)
        - Pleadings
          - Superior Court of Washington for Franklin County, 1988-1990, undated (Box-folder 18/17-24)
          - Court of Appeals, 1990, undated (Box-folder 18/25)
          - Washington State Supreme Court, 1991 (Box-folder 18/26)
        - Exhibits, 1984-1990, undated (Box-folder 18/27-28)
        - Notes, 1987-1989, undated (Box-folder 18/29-19/2)
        - Clippings, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 19/3)
        - Publications, 1988-1990, undated (Box-folder 19/4-7)
      - Washington Pension Union: Pleadings (Canwell Committee; Subversive Activities Control Board), 1948, undated (Box-folder 19/8-10)
      - Williams, Ed (Discrimination), 1983, undated (Box-folder 19/11)
      - Williams, Ernest Lee
        - Appeal of Arson Conviction
          - General Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 19/12)
          - Pleadings, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 19/13-14)
          - Notes, 1975, undated (Box-folder 19/15)
        - vs. King County (Inadequate Medical Care in Prison)
          - General Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 19/16)
          - Pleadings, 1972-1975, undated (Box-folder 19/17-18)
      - Williams, James
        - Workers' Compensation Claim
          - General Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 19/19)
          - Claim History, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 19/20)
          - Pleadings, 1991 (Box-folder 19/21)
        - Anish Lal vs. Estate of James Williams, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 19/22)
      - Williams, Ronald (Black Panther Party), 1970, undated (Box-folder 19/23)
      - Withey, Michael (Disbarment, Caughlan as Amicus Curiae)
        - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box-folder 19/24)
        - Letters of Support, 1976 (Box-folder 19/25)
        - Pleadings, 1976, undated (Box-folder 19/26)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 19/27)
      - Wolf, Hazel (Immigration)
        - Incoming Letters, undated (Box-folder 19/28)
        - Outgoing Letters, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 19/29)
        - Pleadings, 1956-1965, undated (Box-folder 19/30)
        - Transcripts, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 19/31-32)
        - Notes, 1965, undated (Box-folder 19/33)
      - Zilsel, Paul (Illegal Search and Seizure)
        - General Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 20/1)
        - Pleadings, 1975-1976, undated (Box-folder 20/2-3)
        - Police Reports and Witness Statements, 1976 (Box-folder 20/4)
          Includes negatives of photographs of the building and apartment where the disputed search took place.
        - Work in Progress and Hearing Notes (Caughlan's folder title), undated (Box-folder 20/5)
        - Miscellaneous - Grand Jury and Search and Seizure (Caughlan's folder title), 1976, undated (Box-folder 20/6-7)
      - Miscellaneous or Unidentified Cases, 1941-1994, undated (Box-folder 20/8)
      - List of Cases, Caughlan & Hesse, 1953 (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Outgoing Letters
      - To Seattle Post-Intelligencer and Times regarding coverage of accusations against Caughlan by the House Un-American Affairs Committee, 1959 (Box-folder 20/10)
      - To Sally Caughlan, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 20/11)
        Photocopies; written while Caughlan was serving his term at McNeil Island.
      - On Caughlan's Behalf During his Prison Term, 1962 (Box-folder 20/12)
        Possibly written by Hazel Wolf.
      - To the United States President, 1956, 1961 (Box-folder 20/13)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s (Box-folder 20/14)
    - General Correspondence
      - Berner, Richard, Manuscripts Curator, University of Washington Libraries, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 20/15)
      - Goodman, Irvin, 1951 (Box-folder 20/16)
        Regarding the death sentence for Utah and Turman Wilson
      - Howell, Mary, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 20/17)
      - Patricia [last name unknown], 1995-1997 (Box-folder 20/18)
      - Miscellaneous
        - 1950s (Box-folder 20/19-22)
        - 1960s (Box-folder 20/23-24)
        - 1970s (Box-folder 20/25)
        - 1990s (Box-folder 20/26)
          Includes a letter from Lyle Mercer to Ralph Munro, Washington Secretary of State, recommending that John Caughlan be interviewed by the Washington State Oral History Program.
        - Undated (Box-folder 20/27)
    - Writings of Others, 1969, 1985
      - Anonymous (possibly Goldie Caughlan), undated (Box-folder 20/28)
        Found in James Heay file.
      - Best, Norman: Excerpts from a Critique of the Market (joint project with Caughlan), 1992 (Box-folder 20/29)
      - Feldman, Jonathan Marc: No Safe Distance, 1990 (Box-folder 20/30-31)
        First draft of a screenplay about the Domingo-Viernes case.
      - Fox, Kasandra: Cry Against Twilight (On the Insanity of the Human Species) (typescript, inscribed to Caughlan), undated (Box-folder 20/32-34)
      - Herman, Donald III and Graham, Philip Jr.: The Suspect and the Law, 1969 (Box-folder 20/35-37)
      - Hesse, Siegfried: When and How an Alien Can Obtain Release Pending Deportation and Exclusion Proceedings, by Siegfried Hesse, undated (Box-folder 20/38)
      - Jackson, George: Poem, 1977 (Box-folder 20/39)
      - Mathews, Allan J.: The Voice of Time, undated (Box-folder 21/1)
        Family history of Nora Ann and Harold Johnston
      - Nelson, Craig: Craig Nelson on War Crimes Committed by the United States Army in Vietnam, undated (Box-folder 21/2)
      - Rystad, Gus (Translator): Norwegian Poems (typescript), 1985 (Box-folder 21/3)
      - Schroeter, Leonard, 1970, 1996-1998, undated (Box-folder 21/4)
        Includes letters and articles.
      - Teachout, Peter R.: Technological Development and the Legal Process: The Role of the Courts in Consumer and Environmental Protection, undated (Box-folder 21/5-6)
        A collection of materials; contains Caughlan's notes.
      - White, James: Introduction to Legal Expression, 1969 (Box-folder 21/7-8)
        Edited by Peter R. Teachout from materials prepared by James White; used in BGS 200 at the University of Washington
      - University of Washington School of Law: International Protection of Human Rights (Seminar Materials), 1985 (Box-folder 21/9-10)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963, 1984, 1987, 1993-1994, undated (Box-folder 21/11-13)
    - Subject Files
      - Miscellaneous Papers, Letters, Notes Which May Be of Use or Interest (Caughlan's envelope title), 1982-1991, undated (Box-folder 21/14-16)
        The first folder contains Caughlan's index to the materials. A note from Bonita Clarke speculates that these were to be used in some way in Caughlan's writings. Pieces relate to many of Caughlan's continuing interests--Mexico, Central America, the Philippines, rights of indigenous peoples, peace, social justice, socialism.
      - 14th Amendment, undated (Box-folder 21/17)
      - Abraham Lincoln Brigade, 1939, undated (Box-folder 21/18)
      - Apartheid, 1985, undated (Box-folder 21/19)
        Includes a flyer from the National Socialist White People's Party.
      - Black Panther Party, 1966, 1969, 1975, undated (Box-folder 21/20-21)
        Includes a short piece by Caughlan entitled "My Training to Become a Member of the Black Panther Party."
      - Boudin, Kathy, 1982-1986, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 21/22-24)
        Includes three color snapshots of Kathy Boudin and her family.
      - Boudin, Leonard, 1976, 1989, undated (Box-folder 21/25)
      - Braden, Carl (Discrimination in Housing), 1955 (Box-folder 21/26)
      - Central America
        Materials relating primarily to Nicaragua, but also to Guatemala and to the region in general.
        - 1990 Nicaragua trip, 1984-1990, undated (Box-folder 21/27-22/3)
          The purpose of this trip was to observe the 1990 elections, and much of the material relates to this topic.
        - Joint Legal Task Force on Central American Refugees, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 22/4-10)
        - Lawyers Committee against United States Intervention in Central America (LACAUSICA), 1985 (Box-folder 22/11)
        - Salvadoran Teachers Union (ANDES), 1980-1982 (Box-folder 22/12)
        - Miscellaneous American Solidarity Organizations and Events, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 22/13-14)
        - Publications, 1982-1989, undated (Box-folder 22/15-21)
        - Newsletters, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 22/22)
        - Ephemera, undated (Box-folder 22/23, Box:oversize Miscellaneous Oversize Box 9)
          Several posters have been relocated to an oversize box.
        - Clippings, 1985 (Box-folder 22/24)
      - Civil Disobedience Panel (Chaired by Caughlan), 1986 (Box-folder 22/25)
      - Civil Rights Suits - Master File (Caughlan's title), 1971, undated (Box-folder 22/26)
        Includes pleadings and memoranda.
      - Contempt of Court, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 22/27)
      - DeLacy, Hugh and Dorothy, 1969-1992 (Box-folder 23/1-3)
        Includes clippings and ephemera relating to Hugh DeLacy, his political career, and his work with the Committee to Protect the Foreign-Born. Also includes correspondence between Caughlan and Dorothy DeLacy regarding the transfer of DeLacy's papers to the University of Washington Manuscript Collection, and material regarding a memorial to DeLacy.
      - Elections, 1996
        - Draft Ralph Nader for President, 1996 (Box-folder 23/4)